

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- 🔼 Arsen Tabaku
- Munich, Germany
- arsentabaku2@gmail.com
- (+49 176 6697 9019 | +355 68 2621 371
- https://arsentabaku.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-Stack Software Engineer with a track record of excellence in crafting innovative solutions. Currently contributing expertise to VRdirect. Committed to embracing challenges and swiftly mastering new techs, even in high-pressure environments. My journey is marked by a strong grasp of software engineering principles, driving me to create top-quality software that solves real-world problems. Equipped with a natural aptitude for troubleshooting and problem-solving, combined with an analytical and logical mindset.

EDUCATION

15/10/2018 – 30/09/2020 Master degree in Media Computer Science

Saarland University - Saarbrücken (Germany)

22/10/2015 – 19/07/2018 Bachelor degree in Information and Communication Technology (ICT)

University of Tirana - Tirana (Albania)

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/10/2020 - Present (Full-time)

Full-stack Software Engineer at VRdirect GmbH – Munich (Germany)

- Developing features in multiple softwares (web, mobile, desktop).
- Enhancing products quality assurance by developing tests (unit, e2e).
- Supporting the improvement of software architecture.

01/11/2021 - 15/11/2022 (Part-time)

QA Engineer at Curb Hero RE Management – Los Angeles (California, USA)

- Planned, created and managed the overall quality planning strategy.
- Developed comprehensive and detailed e2e/unit test suites.
- Automated execution and generation of easy-to-understand reports.

01/01/2020 - 30/09/2020 (Full-time)

Master Thesis at Cluster of Excellence, HCI lab – Saarbrücken (Germany)

- Conceptualized physics-based metaphors based on users pre-existing knowledge to provide more intuitive and natural interactions.
- Implemented the metaphors in a VR application, based in Unity.
- Conducted a user study to validate the raised hypotheses.

01/03/2020 - 30/09/2020 (Part-time)

Software Developer at ZeMA - Saarbrücken (Germany)

 Developed a VR application to (dis)assemble complex 3D models where employees can practice before using them in the real world.

09/09/2019 - 07/02/2020 (Internship)

Software Developer at DHfPG - Saarbrücken (Germany)

- Developed an interactive virtual tour for a gym where instructors can navigate through to help customers that need assistance.
- Conducted a user study to validate the raised hypotheses.

Coding Mentor at Tirana IT Education – Tirana (Albania)

• Tutored university students subjects like IT basics, Algorithmics and Data Structures and Web programming.

BEST PROJECTS

09/2019 – 02/2020	Developed a VR coaching tool for educating fitness trainers which simulates pre-recorded 3D-environments of a gym in VR where users can navigate to spot customers that need help and answer questions asked within VR.
05/2019 – 08/2019	Developed a Smart Mirror project for HKBSaar and DFKI which detects peoples' faces and augments those by adding hairstyles, hair colors, beards, glasses etc.
02/2019 – 06/2019	Worked on a university project for Scheer GmbH to remotely control a robot's arm via commands given from a virtual reality environment.
10/2018 - 02/2019	Developed a boxing game in VR using my own 3D character. Apart from the game itself, this project had a great focus on having as good UX as possible.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Coding (Angular, Javascript, Typescript, RxJS, NextJs, NestJs, NativeScript, Ionic, Electron, NX)
- QA testing (Cypress, Appium, Cucumber, Jest, Jasmine, Karma, Mocha, JUnit, Browserstack)
- Databases (MongoDB, Firebase, SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL)
- APIs (REST APIs, GraphQL, Swagger, Postman, JSON Server)
- Authentication (OAuth 2.0, JWT, OpenID Connect, Auth0, Azure Active Directory)
- CSS frameworks (Angular Material, Material Design, PrimeNg, Bootstrap, Materialize)
- Modern Development Tools (Jira, Confluence, SourceTree, Git, Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket)
- Software Project Management (SDLC, Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, UML/Sequence/Flow diagrams)
- Software Engineering Principles (Clean Code, SOLID, YAGNI, KISS, DRY, SLAP, Demeter's Law)
- DevOps (CI/CD, Azure DevOps, Docker, Yaml, Bash)
- Operating Systems (MacOS, Windows, Linux)
- IDEs (VS Code, Atom, Sublime, Visual Studio)
- Documentation (Draw.io, UML Diagrams, Zeplin, Latex, Prezi, MS Office, Google package)
- Digital Image Processing (Photoshop CC, Lightroom, Canva, Fotor, Inkscape)

LINGUISTIC PROFICIENCY

Listening	Reading	Speaking	Writing
Native	Native	Native	Native
C1	C1	C1	C1
B1	B1	B1	B1
B1	B1	A2	A2
B1	A2	A2	A2
	Native C1 B1 B1	Native Native C1 C1 B1 B1 B1 B1	Native Native Native C1 C1 C1 B1 B1 B1 B1 A2

SOFT SKILLS

Communication | Quick learning | Hard working | Problem solving | Critical thinking | Work ethic